good evening ladies and gentlemen and a
very warm welcome to icsa Lombard
General Insurance Company Limited Q3 and
9 Monon FY 2025 earnings conference call
from the Senior Management we have with
us today Mr sanjie mantri MD and CEO of
the company Mr gopal balachandran CFO Mr
Girish nyak Chief technology and health
underwriting and claims Mr sandep
Goradia Chief corporate solutions group
Mr Anam singi Chief retail and
government business and Mr G Aurora
Chief underwriting and claims for
Property and
Casualty please note that any statements
comments are made in today's call that
may look like forward-looking statements
are based on information presently
available to the management and do not
constitute an indication of any future
performance as future involved risk and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from the current
views being expressed
as a reminder all participant lines will
be in the listen only mode and there
will be an opportunity for you to ask
questions after the presentation
concludes should you need assistance
during the conference call please signal
an operator by pressing St then zero on
your Touchstone phone I now hand the
conference over to Mr sanjie mantri MD
and CEO IC Lombard General Insurance
Limited thank you and over to you sir
thank you so
much good evening to each one of you
thank you for joining the earnings
conference call of icsa Lombard for
quarter 3 and 9 months financially at
2025 at the outset let me wish you all a
very happy new
year as I complete first year in my
current role I'm excited to share
developments we have made together since
we connected on January 16
2024 we outlined our vision of one is
one team building cohesive teams to
leverage synergies and complimentary
strength to top to tap to new business
opportunities in these Endeavors we
realigned our teams to work
collaboratively under a unified product
and business practice today I'm pleased
to share many of our initiatives such as
one one call center one one digital and
well and one agency have started
yielding results any change of a
significant magnitude requires
continuous reinforcement and we continue
to learn as we co-create an environment
conducive to conducive to growth in
inovation and
collaboration Let Me Now update on
update you on industry Trends and
developments that we have witnessed in
the past few months of financial year
2025 for the quarter ended September
2024 as per the data released by MOS the
GDP growth slowed down to 5.4% as
compared to 8.1% in the corresponding
quarter of previous year let me dwell on
certain key data points during last
quarter which can have an impact on GI
industry at
large on the corporate side the industry
supporting infrastructure and
constructions like steel cement and
Commercial Vehicle sales witness muted
growth as government spending towards
Capital expend capital expenditure
remains luggage which we also which is
also reflecting in the commercial lines
of General insurance
industry on the auto sector the industry
reported muted growth in quarter 3 of
2025 as per CM with growth in private
car at 4 and half % growth in two wheer
at 3% and degrowth in CV at
.5% the retail rimur as reported by S
has seen Improvement in the growth on
account of optic and Rural demand With
Private Car growing at 4 5.9% two wheer
at 12.4% and CV at
1.6% health insurance continues to be
the fastest growing and largest
contributor of the industry in in the
gdpi mix attracting significant
investment across
stakeholders the bank credit growth also
moderated to 11% due to slowdown in
credit to nbfc segment and unsecured
loans in addition the MSI sector growth
also got adversely impacted due to
structural
changes further as we move toward the
next quarter We Believe infra based
spending lower Insurance penetration
enhance risk awareness in a conducive
regulatory environment is expected to
have positive impact on General
Insurance sector over medium to long
term coming to the regulatory update
general insurers are mandated to
recognize premium for long-term products
on a 1 byn basis effective October 1st
2024 as an industry new motor policies
due to long-term TP were recognized on
one by end basis there is thus there is
no impact on this line of business the
premium under long-term health and other
line of business were recognized in the
year of underwriting it s this change
has an impact on the reporting of health
and other line of business for the
industry for quarter three of financial
year
2025 however this does not impact the
economic value so we continue to
evaluate business opportunities which is
expected to deliver sustained returns to
stakeholders secondly on solvency Norms
The Authority issued guidelines on on
inadmissibility of asset which changes
disallowance of receivable Prim from net
basis to gross basis due to this there's
a reduction of 30 basis points in our
solvency ratio as at March 3 as at
December 31st 2024 consequently our
solvency ratio was 2.36 as in December
31st 2024 Which is higher than the
minimum regulatory requirement of 1.5
thus this change does not impact our
growth Journey The General Insurance
Council has represented the matter to
the authority emphasizing the
significant implication of this change
on the solvency position for the
industry players
now coming to the industry growth gross
direct premium income has grown by 99.5%
and 7.8% for quarter three of financial
year 2025 and 9 months Financial year
2025 respectively as published by GI
Council excluding crop and massel
segment the industry registered a growth
of
5.7% and 99.1% for quarter 3 Financial
year 2025 and 9 month 2025 respective
speaking on the specific segments within
the industry during the quarter under
motor insurance the industry GW at 7.6%
for quarter 3 Financial year 2025 the
total numbers of vehicles sold as per CM
data is approximately 3.1 million
Private Car 15 million two wheelers and
1.2 million CV for 9 months Financial
year
2025 the health segment during the
quarter delivered double digit growth
within the group health within this
Group Health viw at 14.6% and Retail
Health viw at 6.6% year on year in
quarter three Financial 2025 further
subdued cred dis verment by financial
institutions has resulted in a slower
growth of Health Business Health Benefit
business the commercial line segment
deew at
8.4% within this the fire contined to
degrow resisting a degrowth of 22% on
account of pricing pressure we expect
the pricing to to improve in the fire
segment in the coming months now
speaking of the underwriting performance
for the industry the comb combined ratio
for the industry was to
113.0 from for H1 of 2025 as against
Triple
1.9% for H1 of 2024 largely on account
of increase in expense
ratio for the motor business the
industry combine ratio was to 24.8% in
H1 financially at 2025 from 119 .4% in h
fun of 2024 I will now speak about the
company's performance across key
business segments during quarter 3
Financial year
2025 the company's gdpi for quarter 3
Financial year 2025 registered a growth
of
4.8% with one by hand accounting Norm
the company registered degrowth of 3% as
again the industry growth of
99.5% during the same period excluding
crop and Mass health the company degre
by . 7% as compared to Industry growth
of
5.7% in commercial line segment we
remain cautious due to continued pricing
pressure resulting in degrowth of
8.6% however we continue to maintain a
market share in the segment further we
have maintained our leadership position
in liability and Marine cargo segment in
motor we grew at 9.4% for quarter 3
Financial year 2025 as against the
industry growth of 7.6%
our growth in this segment was driven by
festive lead Auto Sales as well as old
book during this quarter we sustained a
balanc portfolio with a mix of Private
Car two wheeler and CV at 52.9 26.7 and
20.4
respectively moving to the health
business during the quarter we Vi at
10.3% for quarter 3 Financial year 2025
and with one by n accounting now we
degree at
4.6% within Health a retail Health
segment registered a growth at
44.3% with one by an accounting Norm the
growth was at 19.1% is as against
industry growth of
6.6% during the same period resultantly
we gain market share has reaching 3.2%
in quarter 3 Financial year
2025 as updated updated in our previous
call we continue to invest in product
Innovation and Technology integration
this includes upgrades to Elevate
revamping a super topper product
activate booster and travel product trip
secure plus during the quarter in the
group health employer employee segment
we continue to maintain cautious
approach on account of competitive
intensity resulting in nut growth at
1.1% in quarter three Financial year
2025 our group other business Drew at
1.8% with 1 byn accounting Norm the
degrowth in this segment was at 33%
during the same
period we continue to harness our
digital capabilities to enhance customer
experience leading to a customer facing
digital business growing at growth of
99.9% constituting 7.4% of our overall
gdpi during the quarter our I take care
app has surpassed 13.2 million user
downloads registering a premium of 64.2
million for quarter 3 Financial year
2025 additionally I would like to
highlight efforts to undertaken towards
improving claims efficiencies across
retail line of business our prer partner
Network serviced
73.6% of our non OEM claims in quarter 3
Financial year 2025 as again 67.3 in
quarter 3 of financial year
2024 our average claim settlement period
of retail L of business has seen
Improvement it has improved from six
days in financial year 2024 to 5 days in
9 month Financial year 2025 for motor OD
and from 5 days in financial year 2024
to 3 days in 9 month Financial year 2025
for health our initiative is which was
launched in April of 2024 offer an on
ground support to over 65,000 customers
across 2500 Hospital Network we continue
to monitor our customer feedback from
independent agencies in the form of net
promoter score study on regular basis
our NPS continues to be healthy at 69
and 65 for financial year 2025 for
health and motor claims respectively
supported by a customer trust in one of
the previous update we discussed on a
Core Business and Technology
transformation project project we
initiated transformation journey of our
health business and have now achieved a
critical Milestone by ruling out a
flagship retail Indemnity product
Elevate on our new code platform going
forward we expect a shorter period of
development of products on our new
system
ARS we are excited to see this
extending across our product categories
under the health business and Beyond we
firmly believe project will be a key
enabler of a vision of one is one team
as we conclude we positive and
determined to achieve profitable
outcomes led by multiproduct multi-
distribution strategy focus on product
Innovation data analytics and digital
enhancement with our guiding force of
one is one team I will now request gopal
to take through the financial numbers
for the recent concluded quarter and 9
months thanks sanjie and good evening to
each one of you I will now give you a
brief overview of the financial
performance of the recently concluded
quarter and nine months we have uploaded
the results presentation on our website
you can access it as we walk you through
the performance
numbers with effect from October 1 2024
long-term products are accounted on a 1
byn basis as mandated by the regulator
and quarter 3 and 9 months numbers of
this year are not comparable with prior
periods or prior years please also refer
to slide number 15 of our investor
presentation for further details uh on
this the gross direct premium income of
the company was at rupees 2 26.2 3
billion in 9 months of this year as
againsted 187.5 billion in 9 months of
last year a growth of
10.3% as against the industry growth of
7.8% gdpi was R 62.4 billion in quarter
as against R 62.3 billion in quarter 3
last year a degrowth of 3% as against
the industry growth of
99.5% on the retail set of the business
GDP of motor wases 31.0 n in quarter 3
as againsted R
[Music]
28.425b for motor segment was rupes 36.4
billion as at December 31 2024 as
against 35.13 billion as at September 30
2024 GDP of the health segment was 13.16
billion in quarter 325 as against R 1.79
billion in quarter 324 registering a
degrowth of
4.6% our agents which included the point
of sale distribution count was 1
1477 at December 31 2024 up from 1 lak
33683 as at September 30 2024 GDP of the
commercial lines was
14.63% fi4 registering a degrowth of
88.6% resultantly the combined ratio was
10 12.9% in 9 month
fi25 as against 103.7 in 9 months last
year the combined ratio was 102.7 in
quarter 3 of the current year as
againsted 13.6% in quarter 3 fi 24
excluding the impact of cat losses of
rupes .94 billion in 9 months F525 and
rupes 1.37 billion in 9 month f524 the
combined ratio was 0
2.3% and 10 2.6% respectively excluding
the impact of cat losses of r54 billion
in Q3 f524 the combined ratio was 10
2.3% there were no major catastrophic
losses for Q3
F525 our investment assets during the
quarter Rose to rupes 55.97 billion at
December 31 2024 up from 55.57 billion
at September 30 2024 our investment
leverage net of borrowings was 3.76
times as at December 31 2024 as against
3.91 times at September 30 2024
investment income was at R 33.7 3
billion in 9 months F525 as against
rupes 26.5 7 billion in 9 months f524 on
a quarterly basis investment income was
rupees 11.21 billion in Q3 fi25 as a GED
rupes 8.57 billion in Q3 f524 our
capital gains net of impairment in
investment assets today at 7.96 billion
in 9 month fi25 as compared to rupes 3
95 billion in 9 month f24 capital gains
net of impairment on investment
investment assets stood at rupees 2.76
billion in Q3 fi25 as compared to rupees
1.08 billion in Q3 fi 24 our profit
before tax grew by 42.8% at R 26.5 3
billion in 9 months fi25 as against
rupes
18.57% at r 9 .6 billion in Q3 F525 as
against R 5.74 billion in Q3
f524 consequently profit after tax grew
by
42.9% at rupes 19.99 billion in 9 months
fi this year as against rupes 13.99
billion in 9 month
f24 fat grew by 67.9% at R 7.24 billion
in Q3 fi25 up from rupes 4.31 billion in
Q3 fi 24 return on average Equity was
20.8 % in 9 months this year as against
17.1% in 9 months of the last year the
return on equity for this quarter of the
current year was 21.5% as againsted
15.3% in Q3 fi 24 solvency ratio was at
2.36 times this is after factoring in
the impact of 30 basis points as sanjie
had mentioned as at December 31 2024 as
against 2.65 times as at September 30
2024 which continued to be higher than
the regulatory minimum of 1.5 times as I
conclude I would like to state that we
are aligned with our eor of driving
profitable growth consistent and
sustainable value creation for all our
stakeholders while ensuring that the
interest of policyholders are in the
Forefront at all times I would like to
thank you all for attending this earning
call and we'll be happy to take
questions that you have thank you thank
you very much we will now begin the
question and answer session anyone who
wishes to ask a question may press star
and one on the touchone telephone
if you wish to remove yourself from the
question Q you may press star and two
participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a
question ladies and gentlemen we will
wait for a moment while the question Q
assembles we'll take a first question
from the line of nishin Chate from kotak
institutional equities please go ahead
uh hi uh thanks for uh taking my
question and U you know congrats for a
good set of numbers uh you know just a
little bit of commentary on the motor
side you know we can see the loss ratios
uh you know improving uh for you uh both
on a sequential and annual basis and uh
significant Improvement very
specifically on the third party side uh
so just uh just just if we could give
some commentary in terms of you know
what's happening over here how is the
competitive intensity and I believe we
have gained market share in this quarter
in both the
segments yeah so nin I think uh you're
right I think uh clearly uh over the
last uh few years if You' have seen I
think we have been slightly selective in
the way we have been writing the risks
and therefore to that extent that has
kind of stood Us in times of uh
reflection on the combined outcomes um
having said that I think obviously what
where what we are seeing right now is U
therefore uh renewed opportunities in
the way we can write risks and that's
reflective also in terms of the increase
in the market share that we have seen
relative to 9 months of last year uh
generally if you see I think we have
been able to see particularly let's say
in this particular quarter uh between
new and renewal I think largely the
growth has been more or less similar
when you look at at a category level and
therefore we continue to look for
opportunities in each of Private Car two
wheeler CV and broadly if you look at
the mix it's in line with what we have
normally seen over uh prior periods uh
on the loss experience specifically this
CH I think this is something that we
keep speaking about um obviously when we
kind of uh write or maybe risk select
the portfolio we have an ultimate loss
experience that we kind of uh go with an
assumption at the time of writing the
risk and over a period of time I think
you given the fact that we have
generally been prudent SL conservative
in our loss estimates as the loss
experiences starts to develop I mean we
can see this not just for uh this year
across years uh we have been able to see
let's say favorable loss development and
that starts to getting that starts to
get reflected on the numbers um as we
kind of see across different Financial
periods uh so that's where we are but
broadly if you ask me I think in terms
of the overall loss ratio range that
I've kind of spoken about even in the
past and again as I keep saying uh it's
always better to look at motor as a
category rather than looking at uh own
damage and third party uh independently
and the range that we have spoken about
running overall motor uh in that range
of 65 to 67 I think that's broadly the
range that we believe uh we should
continue to see as an outcome in terms
of the portfolio experience so that's
where we are um and uh and and the
positive news is I think some of the
market participants possibly who had
kind of gone quite aggressive uh in the
past uh you can clearly see most of
those companies when you look at their
individual
month-on-month growth numbers clearly
there is a there has been a element of
calibration that has happened and that's
also reflective in the outcomes that
these companies had to exhibit in some
of their combined ratio outcomes so so
that's where we are we continue to be uh
cautious in building the book and so far
as the ethos on uh writing or selecting
the portfolios continues to remain the
same as in we will keep looking for a
sustained basis an economic output uh
which we think will be viable from a
longer term perspective no absolutely
and also just the thing is uh in our
mindset I we will do what makes sense to
US market share of course this year
looks better but uh uh we also expain
the market maybe almost four quarters
back in terms of why our market share is
where it is so it's more of an outcome
uh of how multiple factors uh work it's
not something uh that we CH keep you
know it's more outcome and as in when it
makes us look good it's primly driven by
an ecosystem development uh as we
continue to pursue what we believe makes
sense for
us and and the Delta this quarter or you
know the the much lower you know loss
ratio in TP this quarter uh you it could
it be uh you know uh maybe because of
better releases this quarter so again as
we keep saying nin I think uh TP again I
have spoken in numerous occasions even
in the past right I think U given that
it's obviously and all of you understand
uh you all have been tracking us pretty
much for a very long period of time uh
so and this is clearly a book which is
much more longtail in terms of loss
development loss experiences obviously
have to be looked at uh over a period of
time and as I said obviously the level
of prudence that we kind of go with in
terms of our reserving estimates that
stand pretty much intact absolutely
absolutely no change in the philosophy
of reserving and therefore as the
portfolio actually starts to experience
outcomes you could see let's say some of
the releases play out at different
periods it could be in a particular
quarter it could be in a particular
Financial year or on an overall basis
which is why if you look at our
reserving triangle now that you also
have a specific uh triangle outcome in
the context of third party as well and
there again you will see consistently
for us there are small amount of
favorable laun development that we have
seen over years this is again not just
for one quarter or one year or uh two
years it's across Financial periods that
we have been able to see some small
amount of uh favorable development and
that and hence to that extent the the
approach to reserving will continue in
terms of a favorable loss development
and that's how we have been kind of
going about uh risk selection as I
talked about and just finally uh in this
backdrop uh you know do we uh really
sort of now expect uh uh tariff hike
third party tariff hike this year so
then again you know well industry
expecting it for last uh few years and
uh it's all something which we control
uh the answer to this is yes we do
expect a hike but can it can can it come
can it not is something which will come
from the regulator as well as moth the
way T prices decided so but we do
believe believe yes it's been 3 to four
years and there might be possibly a hike
at least which you'll get for next
financial
year sure thank you very much and all
the best thank you thank you thank you
ladies and gentlemen in order to ensure
that the management is able to answer
queries from all participants please
restrict your questions to two at a time
you may join back the queue for followup
questions next question is from the line
of PES Jen from MOA loal please go ahead
yeah hi uh congrats on a very good set
of numbers uh just you know just Haring
gopal on this point on uh the loss ratio
on the uh motor side again uh uh so you
were mentioning that for the motor as a
piece we should be looking at a loss
ratio of 65 to
67% uh but we are way below that
currently so would you still say that
you
know the number would be in that range
or we should be that's more of a longer
term uh loss ratio that you would be
looking at uh that's my first question
uh second is on the health loss ratio uh
could you give the give the granularity
on you know how much was the retail
Health loss ratio and how much was the
employer employee uh loss ratio um and
uh just on this you know on the fire
piece you mentioned
that there could be you know price hike
and so so why would that be because your
loss ratio outcomes seems to be pretty
uh controlled at
50.1% uh yeah that would be my question
perfect so maybe I go to the reverse
sequence uh so let me start with the
commercial line um so again PR I think
all of you understand that commercial
lines in general is a relatively High
exposure portfolio so therefore to that
extent uh you can obviously see
experiences which could be relatively
with low frequency High severity
outcomes and therefore again in a given
period you can obviously see experiences
on loss numbers which could be
significantly adverse or maybe at the
same time the portfolio will logically
kind of in case if you don't have large
number of catastrophic events then what
you normally expect as attritional
losses is what how the portfolio will
develop um I think clearly you have seen
not just in the Indian market I think
across the globe you have clearly seen
increased incidences of some of these
catastrophic events impacting insurers
reinsurers customers at large and
therefore clearly when you look at the
overall portfolio outcome from a market
standpoint I think it's leading to an
outcome where the experiences from a
let's say from a reinsurance standpoint
may not be necessarily in that sense
viable at the level of pricing that they
have given to the market at Large so
hence given the fact that some of these
events are more frequent more in numbers
there is obviously a need for the entire
market across stakeholders to look at
what should be the level of price that
you should kind of offer for this
selection uh equally in the past for
example you would have seen periods of
very long periods of soft pricing as
well so that's how the nature of the uh
business is you will obviously see
through various price Cycles at at
sometimes you will obviously as I said
EXP and soft pricing currently it's a
regime where maybe because of these
increased insurances you will see some
bit of hardening in price and hence at
least which is where we we are kind of
coming from um the expectation is at
least so far as the uh quarter 4 and and
more importantly the April 1 renewals
which will largely be the where bulk of
the corporate renewals will happen we do
expect the overall Market to be far more
uh sensible in so far as pricing those
risks are concerned so that's where we
are and that's that's that's what we
believe from an overall positive
sentiment uh to your point on the health
loss breakdown as what uh every quarter
we keep asking for this uh split uh I
think on the corporate Health which is
the ghi segment again I'll will give the
quarter three numbers for the both the
segments first which is Corporate health
and then retail Indemnity so for
corporate heal quarter three of last
year that number was
93.1 that number for this quarter 3 is
at
97.2 and Retail inity numbers last year
was 66% which is down to about 65% on a
9 Monon basis again in the same sequence
corporate Health last year was
95.8 which is currently about
97.7 and the retail inity numbers which
was 65.6 for 9 months last year that
number stands at about
69.1% uh but more than let's say some of
these numbers in general I think what we
have seen is uh uh I think pretty much
we do see uh maybe some continuation of
uh increased incidences of uh claims
playing out uh in the context of uh uh
some of the in the health segment
specifically and therefore in line with
what we had spoken even in quarter one
we said we will obviously observe for
the development of this increased
incidences over the next few quarters uh
so that's where we are and in that
context is where the numbers are for the
health loss numbers your last point on
uh
motor I think the range that we kind of
spoke about at 65 to 67 you're
absolutely right I think that's
obviously the preferred range at which
we would want to kind of run the book
again not just over one or two year
Horizon that's something that we would
want to kind of look at it over a much
more longer term play having said that I
think obviously in now when it comes to
specific Financial periods it could be
purely a function of what kind of mix of
business that you write U and again we
have discussed this in the past you
particularly when it comes to new motor
that typically comes with a relatively
low loss outcome but possibly a slightly
higher cost of acquisition but equally
on the flip side when you kind of start
to Source more of the renewal or let's
say the older book that invariably comes
with a slightly higher loss outcomes but
obviously a lower cost of acquisition so
that's how we manage the overall
portfolio in the way how we see the
market opportunity but over a medium to
long term I think the range that we are
comfortable with to operate with will be
between that 65 67% for motor as a
category got that any price X
contemplating in the health
segment I think that's something that we
keep looking for PR and uh and we have
and we have not shied away from taking a
price change uh you would recollect
again slightly going back to some of our
conversations even in the past U if you
were to go back maybe almost four years
back quarter 3
2021 um at that point of time we did
affect an average price increase of
roughly about 8% on the overall renewal
book and then roughly about one and half
two years thereafter again we had kind
of affected a price increase which range
anywhere between uh 20 to 22% so in
general I think again on the retail
Indemnity book specifically again we
have spoken about the fact that the
range that we are comfortable on running
the book is a loss ratio of around that
range between 65 to 70% more towards I
would say slightly on the highest higher
end of the range U and at this point of
time I think as you would have seen the
outcome largely is kind of playing out
within the range that we are comfortable
with but having said that I think if the
portfolio warrants any kind of a price
division we will not shy away from
taking
one thank you thank you thank you
participants are requested to restrict
to two questions please we have our next
question from the line of sanket Goda
from avenders Park please go
ahead yeah thank you for the opportunity
sir gopal you said that you want to work
motor TP on motor loss ratio in the
range of 60 to 65 if I take at the other
end for motor TP at 65 is it fair to
assume that in Q4 um the loss ratios in
motor TP will be more 70 70 to 75
compared to what you have reported 60.1
uh for 9 months fi25 so that's that's a
fair assumption to make to to remain
conservative with respect to motor TP
reserving again I I mean just for the
sake of uh rate rating I will keep
saying that uh um I would always urge
all of you to look at numbers more over
longer term Horizon uh particularly for
motor third party uh it would be
completely in that sense when I when I
use this to say that uh ideally quarters
will have multiple factors to it um as I
just mentioned one factor would be in
terms of uh the kind of business mix
that we see as an opportunity so that by
itself will determine what the loss
ratio outcome could be uh and as I said
we keep looking for the outcome of the
loss development of the book that we
have written in the past and this is not
just something that we do at a
particular point this is something that
we keep evaluating every quarter um and
that would be true even for quarter four
um and in case if in any of the past
book reflect something better in terms
of outcome then obviously to that extent
you will see some of the uh impact play
out even in quarter 4 as well uh so
hence uh I think rather than talking
about a point estimate or a point number
for a particular period it's better that
we keep looking at which is where I said
the medium to long-term range on motor
as a category uh because again I think
this is something that all of you
understand it's always in that sense
given the fact that motor own damage is
free to price motor third party is fixed
in tariff better to look at motor as a
category rather than trying to even
split between motor own damage and third
party and hence just to kind of rate
medium to long-term range that we
comfortable on running the book will be
between 65 to 66
got it and and the see see you reported
uh 102 on 1 byn uh and and 102.8 on if
you exclude uh 1 byn so so the
management guidance was to end up with
1024 fi25 and probably 101.5 for the
fourth quarter so so even factoring a
bit of negative impact from one by one
do you still continue to maintain that
guidance to play out for the full year
and and and if I take Exit as one1 1.5
for the fourth quarter should we fairly
assume that is the number which will be
there to for 526 and and last and and
the second thing is that if you can
break down the exact growth of motor
into new and old vehicle the way you did
it last
time yeah so maybe I think I'll will
give you the numbers for uh new and old
this is again I'm just kind of giving
you for quarter three uh so new was uh
again 9.5 which is what I just mentioned
in response to one of the calls largely
the numbers were similar
uh 99.5% growth for new and almost a
similar number of 9.3% for the old so as
a category the overall growth was
99.4% okay and on the guidance part s
that you spoke about uh clearly as we
had put across as to where we want to
finish the whole year uh at that point
of time uh there was no visibility that
one by will come and when such changes
happen the configuration of product
which we procure from the market also
can go through a transformation uh
there's no reason to believe that dially
we are not there but at the same time we
also have to evaluate what the
opportunity comes through so it's a
combination of all these aspects that
will uh decide the way forward its early
days is the first quarter where the
industry and us are giving numbers which
are on a one by
basis and the strange part is the
configuration where the first six months
are not on one by and this quarter is
one by and so to that extent it will uh
it will play out over the course of time
and the industry uh performance which we
spoke about and I said has moved to 113
uh whereas it was 111 so it's kind of
relatively got versed off so all of
these factors will also weigh but what
we also stay committed is besides the
combine the RO range that we want to
operate which we spoke about it uh when
we have met so it's a combination thing
which will keep keeping us excited in
terms of doing selection
also okay perfect that's it from my side
thank you thanks thank you next question
is from the line of nides Jen from
investtech please go
ahead uh thanks for the opportunity the
first question is on this one byn has
the impact has been passed on to the
distributor and uh so are they also
getting Commission on a yearly basis and
uh do you expect any impact on the
business growth because
that uh the answer is yes it's
Regulatory and whatever needs to be done
is done so it will be also taken where
the annuity commission payment will
happen to the distributor uh as far as
growth is concerned uh there is an
overarching impact in terms of long-term
product being sold but internally from
an our organization perspective the
economic value that comes in selling uh
the long-term product stays intact so we
continue to pursue uh in the market uh
selling long-term products the
accounting part of it will emate as in
when it happens
and so this is I think I think the only
thing that I just add to what sanjie
rightly said I think uh uh this is the
first quarter uh and and therefore to
that extent the market practices will
also see an evolution um in terms of
some of these changes uh uh that gets
played out so for example when 6 years
back when the regulator had mandated
let's say third party mandatory for 3
years 5 years
uh in between there were changes uh in
terms of the product construct to get
motor line of business recognized on a
one by prescription similar to what you
see for the rest of the lines as we
speak today uh so those practices
obviously kind of evolve over a period
of time and hence we will obviously
watch the market development very very
closely um obviously I think the the
intent when you look at it from a
regulatory standpoint I think is very
very positive uh in the way they have
kind of uh wanted this particular change
and therefore our practices will be very
clear to make sure that uh we clearly
kind of meet regulatory expectations but
obviously we will keep a very close
watch on Market developments as well and
keep kind of taking actions
corresponding to them yeah and also if I
was a distributor and if I'm able to do
a long-term Health there is no reason
because it is VMA and that should go
through a
change what you're not getting in one
year on the front end business you will
get over three years so there an annuity
income uh that will flow over a period
of time so there is there can be a
shortterm thought process if you're not
getting it you may not want to pursue
with it hopefully better FS will prevail
and they will also look at economic
value and go ahead and sell long term uh
as always
required uh sure uh uh second question
is on the reinsurance uh the retention
ratio has increased quite materially
this quarter uh to 82% uh so is there
any change in strategy with respect to
reinsurance
so honestly there
is so if you ask us our insurance
programs typically gets decided at the
beginning of the year I think as what we
have mentioned earlier as well uh and U
again purely it's it's a function of uh
what is a split between mix of corporate
mix of retail and within that uh if you
recollect in the past we have spoken
about let's say in the context of Health
for example on health Indemnity as a
line of business we have always operated
without in that sense leave aside the
obligatory which is true for everyone in
the market but other than the obligatory
reinsurance we don't have any other
reinsurance requirements from a health
inity standpoint on health benefit as a
category not just again this year across
years we have obviously kind of operated
on a reinsurance structure U and hence
and if you recollect particularly not
just again this quarter this year in
general I think the health benefit
segment has seen an impact on grow
growth and therefore to that extent that
will obviously have an impact on the net
retention numbers so that's one second
for whatever it is even quarter 3 does
have an element of corporate business as
well it's not that corporate business
comes down to zero and there the
approach for us again if you look at it
over a 9 Monon basis we have been very
very selective largely we have tried to
kind of hold on to maintaining market
share in that particular category and uh
given the fact that that particular
business is slightly in that
in that sense subdued that again kind of
contributes to the overall retention
numbers but if you see the overall
retentional number the way we kind of
look at it I mean on the net premium to
uh gross premium I think at least if you
look at it on a 9 Monon basis at least
the number stands at roughly I'm talking
about the current year uh if you look at
it on a even with the 1 byn uh impact uh
I think the retention numbers will be
roughly at about 72% I think that's
where we are and to answer your point no
change in the reinsurance strategy
nothing specific it's not a case where
we had an element of reinsurance for the
first six months or something and
suddenly we have decided to kind of
change our approach to reinsurance uh
nothing no significant change therein
and the other aspect is the bulk of the
reinsurance renewal conversations will
now happen in quarter four for the next
financial
year okay and last question is on claims
to I'm sorry to interrupt NES can you
please join back the que okay sure thank
you sure
thanks we have a next question from the
line of jant kot from Jeff please go
ahead uh thank you for the
opportunity canet mode please not very
clear thank you for the opportunity uh
first question is on the competitive
scenario uh given that we are
approaching the E Glide path uh last
couple of uh quarters how do you see it
play out over the next year and
specifically the impact on that is
having on Group Health and fire uh and
what would be our sort of stance in in
in case it intensifies uh going into the
next say four to six quarters uh that's
the first question I'll come back with
the second one so J clearly on the our
stand has been pretty clear on that uh
we continue to operate within the um
guidelines and there is no reason under
any circumstances we will like to
violate that uh as in when we see
intensity building up uh we will choose
to withdraw rather than participate in
that kind of uh you know uh business
intensity another point is that the
regulator has taken certain actions so
in terms of expecting companies which
are not within the um guidelines to fall
in line uh with that there is
possibility that it will get disciplined
and will not see Russian pricing if you
see business lines like ghi and some
others uh further going low we would
exchange rather than participant so we
have absolute clarity as a team uh to
let go what is not making commercial
sense for
us uh so do you see this uh playing out
in the claims of your competition and
and by when do you expect some more
rationality on the pricing in these
products uh any any timeline see we we
no one to judge in terms of what
everyone else will do but that being
said uh we did speak about where fire
went and where fire is expected to be so
uh anything which goes below a threshold
uh will tend to autoc correct itself uh
as it's not uh
viable it's it will play out look it
will play out it's not that it will not
play out but there's a point of time
when others will and we respect that we
like to fall in line for umf and manage
this subsequently as in when things grow
up but by sheer presumption is that each
one of us who operates in the industry
wants to run the business in a
profitable Manner and sense will prevail
over a period of
time so second question is on IFRS uh we
know we haven't we know we've guided at
least indicated on some improvement on
the combined ratio uh but it's been uh
you almost three four quarters now uh
any any more uh disclosures or any
anything that you have gone back and and
can help us understand what could be the
possible impact so on I forus obviously
as in the rules come in we will fall in
line uh there is there is no question of
the not falling in line they've also
spoken about the overall benefit it can
have on account of discounting of
reserving and also deferred you know
expenses coming into play it will
aminate in time to come but one
fundamental thing which we all have to
understand is that this is just mode of
accounting right the economic value that
gets given whether it's one by whether
it's IFRS all of it is part of the
process in which manner you will do the
accounting of it the business being
sought the long-term value that is to
get created they all remain similar you
can project this numbers in multiple
manner it doesn't change how we want to
operate it's not that IFRS will change
the manner in which you want to do
business we still will like to do what
we are pursuing at this point of time so
there is excitement of uh that coming
through and we will be more than happy
we in fact we are very clear to say that
why only large everybody in the industry
should start publishing on IFRS basis
any indicat timeline by when will you to
join back the que please as we other
participants waiting thank you thank
you next question is from the line of
subramanyan Aer from Morgan Stanley
please go
ahead um hi uh thanks for the
opportunity uh I had an accounting
question so on slide number 15 you have
given basically the comparison between
uh profits excluding 1 byn and without
in with 1 byn um and U you have given
the gdpi and Pat so uh Pat is actually
higher under the with one by impact so
is it fair to conclude that your uh
commissions are lower because of defs
under with 1 byn method and that's what
is resulting in the higher
profits so again uh uh this is again
which is why I kind of responded to say
that uh the prescription under one by
need not necessarily be uh in terms of
outcome uh go in the direction of only
an increase in profits uh because again
this will be a function of uh what kind
of business mix that you Source uh what
is the kind of reinsurance structures
that you may have in practice uh and
what is the kind of acquisition cost
that you kind of relate to with respect
to sourcing any of those businesses so
there are multiple factors which will
drive let's say an outcome when you look
at it from a transition to a 1 byn slash
without a 1 byn uh uh outcomes now
talking specific in the context of
quarter three I think obviously this has
been a quarter where we were just kind
of talking about in general I think the
credit link dispersements uh across
financial institutions have clearly been
muted and obviously to that extent and
we have been one of the key writers of
some of those risks and that's an area
where I said we have always been
historically operating also with the
reinsurance structur the fact that the
business growth has been relatively
subdued obviously that does have an
impact both in terms of
growth in premiums and therefore
correspondingly the impact that it has I
mean when you look at 1 byn effectively
the prescription is to say that whatever
acquisition cost that you incur you
defer it over the contract period
similarly if there's an element of
reinsurance income that you may have
that is something again you defer it
over the policy contract so in a quarter
if you do see businesses where you
already had an element of a insurance
Arrangement and if that business gets
subdued then therefore the relative
impact in outcome will not necessarily
be the same as compared to a line of
business for example in quarter 3 we
also have contracts of other lines of
businesses where we don't have a re
Insurance Arrangement but there's a cost
of acquisition and by this very inherent
nature of a transition to 1 byn the cost
gets defer there is nothing in terms of
income for us to kind of defer over the
policy period leave aside the obligatory
that's a very very small component so
that's the reason why you see an outcome
for quarter three in terms of profits to
be higher than what you would have
normally reported on a with one by an
approach now this can change going ahead
if let's say the proportion of mix of
businesses undergo a change in terms of
the various factors that I spoke the
outcome could be either reversed you
could possibly see a situation of
neutrality in terms of no change in
profits or equally you could see maybe
an outcome similar to what you're seeing
for quarter 3 this year so lot of moving
Parts uh so hence that ex very difficult
to say attribute uh any specific reasons
but quarter three this is the reason it
has been more more businesses which are
long-term hard the ones where there are
only cost of Acquisitions to be amored
but relatively there are no reinsurance
commissions to
be thanks that's very clear um I wish
you all the best thank you thanks thank
you next question is from the line of
maduka Lada from noama wealth management
please go
ahead uh hi congratulations on a very
good set of numbers uh couple of
questions from me first
see I see a very sharp increase in
commission uh cost now uh can you
explain what has led to that and second
is um in the new 1 byn uh now you know
that that's the way we will be reporting
numbers so what should our uh guidance
be in terms of you know uh exit in Q4
for Combined ratio and also then uh what
are we looking at uh
for the next uh few years so yeah you
know some help on that would be uh very
very useful yeah so mukar again um I
mean I will always keep again kind of
urging all of you to look at uh numbers
more on a combined ratio of prescription
rather than even looking at uh breakdown
of that combined into loss ratio and
let's say maybe the expense ratio and
within that you are maybe asking a
question which is more further breakdown
on uh commission numbers corresponding
to that um so so that so given the
nature of the business that we have you
will obviously see a mix of outcome as I
just mentioned Q3 in specific uh I think
you have seen on bit say for whatever
corporate business that we used to write
in the past that particular part of the
business has been muted and therefore to
that extent you will obviously see a
relatively lower cost of uh acquisition
uh which otherwise would have been there
had that particular growth of commerci
business being there in quarter 3 and
hence the large part of quarter 3 are
businesses which are fundamentally
driven in so far as the retail line of
opportunity is concerned and to quarter
three in general if you see is a period
of festive season uh so when you kind of
put both of this together you will
obviously find an outcome in terms of
even in the context of just the
commission numbers or let's say the
commission ratio you will obviously
possibly see an increase there in but at
the end of the day even as what Sanji
mentioned I think for us I think what
what what is something that we are very
very conscious of is to make sure that
we run the overall operations at an
expense of management which cannot kind
of exceed 30% so that's that's a guard
guard rail for us is something that we
are very very conscious of and two and
more importantly I think for us we will
obviously keep looking for outcomes in
the form of combined ratios on
businesses and at the end of the day we
are all here to give as what we have put
also in the opening remarks which is a
sustained uh return on capital for
stakeholders uh so that's equally
important from an Roe outcome is
something that again we are very very
conscious of I think the range that we
have spoken about is to be within that
range of 16 to 18% and as things it
starts to improve relative to the market
obviously we would want to see that
getting better as well so those are
those are guard Rays within which we
kind of operate with u and hence to that
extent I would again urge each of you to
look at outcomes with some of these uh
uh guard rails as a benchmark and point
on what would be the outcome on quarter
four combined and maybe let's say as we
head into the next financial year I
think sanjie already kind of responded
to that in response to one of the
earlier questions I think again as we
keep saying let's say when we look at
quarter four two factors one we
obviously have to wait and see how the
environment play because that EXT that's
a variable second I think we will have
to see how the market responds I think
what we have said our our combin will
again be uh in relation to the industry
outcomes at least the first half seems
to indicate that the market is slightly
more ver compared to 111 it's at about
113 so we will wait and see how quarter
three numbers are for the other players
in the market and corresponding to that
is how our own quarter 4 outcomes will
play out but what we are conscious of I
think in all fairness when we look at
maybe just the return on uh Equity to
stakeholders I think the broad comfort
that we can give you is we should
definitely end the year within that
range of about 16 to 18% and as we head
into the next year the approach to
writing risk will still remain the same
and then we will keep looking for
profitable opportunity I'll give you a
small perspective sobly you'll get a
better understanding of what gopal also
is talking about it if you look at a
last year number even before that
commercial business for us was uh
clearly you know uh doing a very good
growth numbers and you know that
commercial business overarchingly Works
in a combined ratio Which is far lower
so when they got when we started working
on the planning for this year itself we
had a believe that commercial line per
se will remain secular on the
contribution which is what gopal also
you know eluded in this conversation I
think stand it's not commercial line
which
has grown but the retail line of
business which is you know we're talking
about retail inity we're talk motor
business which has given us growth and
when the configuration changes it's
pertinent to understand that the combine
ratio will also change but the overall
value that we want to give the
stakeholder may not get in Ed at all so
the so the operation with combine ratio
I do understand from your angle but how
we look at businesses has to be
understanding a far more comprehensive
manner to give a particular level of
targeted Roe they will be changes if you
struck to the same plan maybe would we
would have done what is required on
retail still struck to a low growing
growth so we would have done a much
lesser uh Top Line as well as sh a
better combine but it would not have
served the purpose so the point that
gopal keeps making is look at the
business in a far more comprehensive
manner we will have to stay agile in
terms of what opportunities gets
provided we do not want to while we do
give guidance and we did speak about it
we don't want to get ourselves tied down
because we have had X combin number we
let go an opportunity which will serve
us much better in long term it's an
overarching thought which I want to put
across and why we'll have to also real
time change our plans as the market uh
uh you know forces us to react
understood sir got it I'll I'll come
back in the que the yeah thank you thank
you thank you next question is from the
line of Rishi junjun Wala from iifl
institutional equities please go ahead
yeah thank you for the I'm sorry to
interrupt Rishi I request you to
restrict to one question please thank
you okay I'll make it a long one thank
you so uh so just you know firstly um
you know on the investment leverage
right so if we look at it it's already
down to 3.7 77 for us and there has been
a sharp decline in the last 6 months and
this is despite the fact that you know
I'm assuming that motor vehicle act
related benefits haven't really
completely played out as yet so just
wanted to understand your thoughts in
terms of uh you know with or without uh
that implementation on a pan India basis
where do you see uh the investment uh
level average uh you know stable out or
stabilize and a and a related question
to that is um you know 2 three years ago
we had given up this uh 20% Roe and 100%
combin ratio uh Target in order to
ensure that we are not missing out on
growth opportunities given that we are
now at 20% Roes and uh uh combined
ratios are you know trending closer to
100 I mean we are still 200 bips away um
do you think there could be a
recalibration to that Target um you know
in the medium
term so uh so Rishi let me take again
the reverse
sequence uh uh so I think if you ask us
uh the the the uh narrative in terms of
our intent to keep looking for
profitable growth opportunities Remains
the Same so therefore to that extent um
to be stand committed to staying within
that return on Equity objective of
course I think that pretty much kind of
St
intax um and that's the range why I kind
of talked about uh in the medium term
given the level of combine we should be
kind of getting to an outcome which
could be between 16 to 18% the reason
why I'm saying this is because U you
will still appreciate the fact that we
don't want to
lose opportunities for investment in
areas which will Propel growth for uh in
the future uh so that's something that
we are very very conscious of and
therefore these Investments which we
have been kind of speaking through even
in the past will entail an ainting of
expense in the pns and that by itself
when you look at it from an just from an
Year's outcome it will possibly look at
maybe an Roe which may not be equal
exactly to 20% for that matter of fact
but but these are investments which we
think is something that we should make
at this point of time the uh the effect
of which will play through maybe over
the next two three years uh but if you
ask us again the point that we keep
saying I think uh the economic objective
in terms of what we want to write
clearly is within that uh range of Ro
objective that I responded in uh
response to one of the earlier questions
same thought process on combin I think
uh the lens with which we look at each
of the business opportunity again not
just any particular line across lines I
think the lens that we kind of apply is
obviously combined and equally
ultimately the uh returns that would
would kind of fetch to stakeholders for
the capital that is being infused so
obviously that both of this doesn't has
not fundamentally changed and we kind of
stand committed to the range that we
have kind of spoken through uh but all
of this have to be looked at in the
context of how the market operates U and
hence to that extent uh this may be
something that you will see playing out
over long term assuming the market start
responding sensibly but but at times in
case the market uh responds more
aggressively uh in terms of competition
then to that extent maybe some of this
metes will possibly get postponed by a
year or two so that's where we are um on
the first point the investment leverage
I think again um this is again if you
look at the way the leverage gets
computed obviously there is a numerator
which is the investment assets and the
denominator which is let's say net worth
U and then investment assets is
obviously in the context of the various
Investments some of these Investments
are carried at a market value and these
are Point estimates at a point of time
and as you would have seen particularly
since you're looking at the numbers on a
quarter three basis for examp example uh
we have seen obviously particularly
Equity markets relatively exhibiting a
slightly more subdued sentiment and in
that context I think if you look at
maybe the market to market position that
we would have had of the book as at
September relative to as of December
obviously at a point of time that number
would have seen us uh seen us seen a
decline uh so that would have some some
impact when you look at the investment
leverage second I think again as what we
have been speaking there has also been a
relative slowdown in growth uh in
general for us and that by itself
clearly also contributes to the overall
uh available cash flows and that has
also had an impact in the overall
investment leverage and third I think
again clearly when you look at um
particularly for some of the commercial
lines which generally is very very
profitable that's also been a segment
where we have not seen as much of growth
as what one would have expected so all
these factors is where we are on The
Leverage but as the environment improves
we should start seeing the leverage kind
of coming back and also just small thing
uh thanks gopal is that that motor
vehicle act that you refer to receive is
a faster ination then they there'll be a
lower investment leverage not higher so
uh that's one small thing it's more
driven by cash flow and configuration in
terms of the nature of business that
comes through ironically as much I don't
want to but if you have a growth of Pat
also that buget that denom the Networth
will go up and that itself will lead to
investment leverage going down I mean
it's more mathematical in that sense
what I'm saying but there multiple
things will go in uh it's again an
outcome we do understand the value of
Leverage in your mind uh but we write
business in terms of what makes sense
and this comes out as an outcome we do
it's not that we don't look at cash flow
but that is not the reason why we end up
writing certain businesses or eliminate
any
businesses okay thank you so much thank
you thank you we request participants to
restrict to one question please we'll
take the next question from the line of
Aina sing from MK Global please go
ahead yeah thanks for the opportunity
great set of numbers just one question
again coming to that I mean I recall
your kind of a focus on combine not uh
scale C and expenses but more on the
expenses if you put together I mean uh
one that is regulator now kind of
looking for any kind of a change with
their um targets because the rule of
game has been changing in between uh
with this one on by in accounting and if
you can help us I mean even on a kind of
a commission plus opic basis which are
the business lines particularly that is
seeing a bit of I would say intensified
payouts or competition on in terms of
payout that is leading to this overall
op including commission
increase thank yeah so so again uh on
the on the uh on the point on uh ainash
uh uh
so uh so the firstly at this point of
time I think obviously I don't think the
regulator is contemplating anything
specific in terms of uh any change in
the thought process I think uh as a
regulator I think what they're looking
for is uh to make sure that the overall
industry operates within a defined
thresholds uh and at this point of time
that number stands at about 30% or 35%
as the case may be uh and there is this
has been just put into practice maybe
since the last one year or so so to that
extent to expect anything suddenly
changing given even the given the change
that they have put in the context of 1
byn or there about at least that's
something that's not within our
knowledge in terms of whether the
regulator is looking for any specific
changes to be made so at this point of
time the limit of 30 or 35 stands intact
having said that I think what we at
least understand uh from the market is
uh the regular is obviously keeping a
very very close watch on making sure
that the larger market players continue
to make need to make sure that they run
their overall operations at an a Which
is less than 30 or 35 as the case may be
and if you look at basis public uh
disclosure of uh Financial outcomes
still there are a large number of
players who even on an fi 24 basis have
exceeded the threshold and clearly from
Market we understand that the regulator
has asked each of these companies to
come out with a plan of action to make
sure that they are able to kind of come
come within the threshold so that is
where we are uh we don't think there is
going to be anything immediate in so far
as Chang in the expectations on meeting
the limits on expense of management is
concerned from a market
perspective your second point on uh what
are the business lines that invariably
kind of contributes to let's say a high
expense of management again multiple
factors uh so for example the point that
I made saying that if you make any uh
investments in opportunities for the
future now that entails a cost that will
be a part of my expense of management
numbers today so that will put that will
increase the uh ratio second in terms of
the mix of business that you write which
is what I explained earlier if I'm
writing let's say an old relatively new
portfolio on the motor side that
invariably comes with maybe a low loss
ratio High expense so that will let's
say result in an higher EXP expense
numbers and the third will be again
given the fact that we are driving a lot
more on retail health so that invariably
comes with a slightly higher cost of
acquisition so multiple moving parts and
that's the reason why I keep saying look
at more on combined as compared to just
the expense rtio
numbers okay clear thank you thank you
thank you ladies and gentlemen that was
the last question for today I now hand
the call over to Mr sanjie manle for
closing comments over to you sir great I
think uh thank you so much for joining
us it's always a pleasure and your
questions also give us tremendous
Clarity uh we look forward to
interacting with uh each one of you over
the course of next few weeks uh look
forward to your support as always and
have a great year ahead thank you so
much bye-bye thank you thank you on
behalf of icsa Lombard General Insurance
company that concludes this conference
thank you for joining us and human AR
disc connect your lines